<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Luyao Peng&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Luyao Peng&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>State Space Model for Sequential Data</title>
      <link>/post/state-space-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/state-space-model/</guid>
      <description>A state space model defines the hidden state at time \(t\), \(z_t\), to be a linear function of the input at time \(t\), \(u_t\), and the hidden state at time \(t-1\), \(z_{t-1}\), and defines the output at time \(t\) to be a linear function of the hidden state \(z_t\). The model can be written as
\[\begin{equation} \begin{array}{rcl} \mbox{Transition model} \mathbf{z}_t &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \mathbf{A}_t \mathbf{z}_{t-1} + \mathbf{B}_t\mathbf{u}_t + \mathbf{\epsilon}_t \\ \mbox{Observation model} \mathbf{y}_t &amp;amp;=&amp;amp; \mathbf{C}_t\mathbf{z}_t + \mathbf{D} \mathbf{u}_t + \mathbf{\delta}_t \\ &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \mathbf{\epsilon}_t \sim N(\mathbf{0}, \mathbf{Q}_t), \mathbf{\delta}_t \sim N(\mathbf{0}, \mathbf{R}_t) \end{array} \end{equation}\]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Bayesian Neural Network</title>
      <link>/post/empirical-bnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/empirical-bnn/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian approaches to neural networks (BNNs) training [1] have gained increased popularity in NLP community due to its merits of scalability, providing inference uncertainty, and its ensemble learning nature. Despite those features, BNNs are sensitive to the choice of prior and require to tune the parameters in the prior distribution assumed for model weights and biases [2][3]. Sensitivity to the prior and its initialization makes BNNs difficult to train in practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doubly Stochastic Deep Gaussian Process</title>
      <link>/post/doubly-deep-gp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/doubly-deep-gp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gaussian Process Classification by Tensorflow-probability</title>
      <link>/post/gpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gpc/</guid>
      <description>In binary classification, a response function (or a link function) is used to turn the output of a regression model into class probability, so the domain of the output from a regression model is squashed into [0, 1] range. Common link function is logistic function (another one is probit function, which will not be discussed here). For a data point \((x_i, c_i)\),
\[ p(c_i|x_i, w) = \frac{1}{1+exp(-x_i&amp;#39;w)} = \sigma(x_i&amp;#39;w) \]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KPCA for One-class Classification in Automated Essay Scoring and Forensic Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/kpca-for-one-class-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kpca-for-one-class-classification/</guid>
      <description>One-class classification problem is useful in many applications. For example, if people want to diagnoze the healthy condition of machines, measurements on the normal operation of the machine are easy to obtain, and most faults will not haveoccurred so one will have little or no training data for the negative class. Another example is web security detection, people only have data for normal web behavior , since once abnormal behavior occurs, the web security will be attacked, which is a situation people try to prevent from happening.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>