<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Projects on Luyao Peng&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/categories/my-projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Projects on Luyao Peng&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/my-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: KPCA for one-class classification in automated essay scoring and forensic analysis</title>
      <link>/post/kpca-for-one-class-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kpca-for-one-class-classification/</guid>
      <description>One-class classification problem is useful in many applications. For example, if people want to diagnoze the healthy condition of machines, measurements on the normal operation of the machine are easy to obtain, and most faults will not haveoccurred so one will have little or no training data for the negative class. Another example is web security detection, people only have data for normal web behavior , since once abnormal behavior occurs, the web security will be attacked, which is a situation people try to prevent from happening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: NLP in Automated Essay Scoring</title>
      <link>/post/nlp-in-automated-essay-scoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nlp-in-automated-essay-scoring/</guid>
      <description>In The Data Incubator, my capstone project was NLP in automated essay scoring, which was completed in Nov,2018, at that time, I haven’t learned the techniques of NLP with deep learning, so this project only involves basic NLP methods such as BOW, n-gram and tree-based boosting model.
Link to the MMeM github
(The heroku platform only allows 30s response time for any request, sometimes the app takes takes more than 30s to respond due to an external API, please try multiple times to get the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Package “MMeM”: Multivariate Mixed-effects Model</title>
      <link>/post/multivariate-mixed-effects-model-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/multivariate-mixed-effects-model-r-package/</guid>
      <description>This package estimates the variance covariance components for data under multivariate mixed effects model using multivariate REML and multivariate Henderson3 methods. See Meyer (1985) doi:10.2307/2530651 and Wesolowska Janczarek (1984) doi:10.1002/bimj.4710260613.
It is available on CRAN and my github page:
Link to the MMeM github
Link to the MMeM CRAN
The package supports the variance covariance component estimations for the multivariate mixed effects model for one-way randomized block design with equal design matrices:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>