<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Luyao Peng&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Luyao Peng&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R Package “regrrr”: Compiling and Visualizing Regression Results</title>
      <link>/post/regrrr-one-stop-r-toolkit-for-compiling-regression-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/regrrr-one-stop-r-toolkit-for-compiling-regression-results/</guid>
      <description>This is an R package “regrrr” on Cran I coauthored with Rui Yang.
In strategy/management research, we always need to compile the regression results into the publishable format and sometimes plot the moderating effects. This package does the job.
Here is the quickstart guide.
 
Installation To install from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;regrrr&amp;quot;) library(regrrr) You can also use devtools to install the latest development version:
devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;raykyang/regrrr&amp;quot;) library(regrrr)  Examples compile the correlation table library(regrrr) ## Warning: package &amp;#39;regrrr&amp;#39; was built under R version 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: KPCA for one-class classification in automated essay scoring and forensic analysis</title>
      <link>/post/kpca-for-one-class-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kpca-for-one-class-classification/</guid>
      <description>One-class classification problem is useful in many applications. For example, if people want to diagnoze the healthy condition of machines, measurements on the normal operation of the machine are easy to obtain, and most faults will not haveoccurred so one will have little or no training data for the negative class. Another example is web security detection, people only have data for normal web behavior , since once abnormal behavior occurs, the web security will be attacked, which is a situation people try to prevent from happening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Package “MMeM”: Multivariate Mixed-effects Model</title>
      <link>/post/multivariate-mixed-effects-model-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/multivariate-mixed-effects-model-r-package/</guid>
      <description>This package estimates the variance covariance components for data under multivariate mixed effects model using multivariate REML and multivariate Henderson3 methods. See Meyer (1985) doi:10.2307/2530651 and Wesolowska Janczarek (1984) doi:10.1002/bimj.4710260613.
It is available on CRAN and my github page:
Link to the MMeM github
Link to the MMeM CRAN
The package supports the variance covariance component estimations for the multivariate mixed effects model for one-way randomized block design with equal design matrices:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>