<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Name Entity Recognition on Luyao Peng&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/name-entity-recognition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Name Entity Recognition on Luyao Peng&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/name-entity-recognition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Bayesian Neural Network</title>
      <link>/post/empirical-bnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/empirical-bnn/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian approaches to neural networks (BNNs) training [1] have gained increased popularity in NLP community due to its merits of scalability, providing inference uncertainty, and its ensemble learning nature. Despite those features, BNNs are sensitive to the choice of prior and require to tune the parameters in the prior distribution assumed for model weights and biases [2][3]. Sensitivity to the prior and its initialization makes BNNs difficult to train in practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS224n/assignment3/: RNN/GRU Name Entity Recognition</title>
      <link>/post/rnn_ner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/rnn_ner/</guid>
      <description>This post deals with the name entity recognition task using RNN model. The RNN model for NER Let \(\mathbf{x}_t\) be a one-hot vector for word at time \(t\), define \(\mathbf{E}\in \mathbb{R}^{V\times D}, \mathbf{W}_h \in \mathbb{R}^{H\times H}, \mathbf{W}_e\in \mathbb{R}^{D\times H}, \mathbf{U} \in \mathbb{R}^{H\times (C=5)},\mathbf{b}_1\in \mathbb{R}^{H}, \mathbf{b}_2 \in \mathbb{R}^{C}\), the RNN model to make prediction at time step \(t\) can be expressed as \[\mathbf{e}^t = \mathbf{x}^t\mathbf{E}\\ \mathbf{h}^t = \sigma(\mathbf{h}^{t-1}\mathbf{W}_h + \mathbf{e}^t\mathbf{W}_e+\mathbf{b}_1) \\</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CS224n/assignment3/: Window-based Name Entity Recognition (Baseline Model)</title>
      <link>/post/window_based_name_entity_recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/window_based_name_entity_recognition/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This assignment built 3 different models for named entity recognition (NER) task. For a given word in a context, we want to predict the name entity of the word in one of the following 5 categories:
 Person (PER): Organization (ORG): Location (LOC): Miscellaneous (MISC): Null (O): the word do not represent a named entity and most of the words fall into this categroy.  This is a 5-class classification problem, which implies a label vector of [PER, ORG, LOC, MISC, O].</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>